Emergency! Emergency!
大変 大変！
The band we had scheduled can't perform!
出演バンドが出れないって！
Are you kidding?!
マジかよ？
How will we find a replacement?
バンドの代わりは どうする？
Perhaps I could be of some assistance?
私が弾きましょうか？
Y-You're...
あっ あなたは…
I forget the name,
but the girl from Class 2—
名前は思い出せないけど
確か ２組の！
The name's Gotoh.
後藤です
Gotoh-sama!
後藤様～！
Hold me!
抱いて～！
You're a living national treasure!
お前が人間国宝！
ごと～う！　ごと～う！
Gotoh! Gotoh!
うはっ！
...six votes for a haunted house,
お化け屋敷が６人
駄菓子屋さんが２人…
and two votes for a candy shop.
How long have I been out?
いつから寝てたんだろ
I think I was in homeroom, and they started
talking about festival project ideas...
確か ホームルームで
文化祭のことを決める
って言ってて…
It's no use.
ダメだ
Everything after the word
"unity" came up is a blank.
“一致団結”ってワードが
出たところから記憶が…
Okay! So by majority vote,
２組の出し物は
メイド･執事喫茶に決まりました
Class 2's project will be
a maid and butler cafe!
はっ？
We'll have to get lots of maid uniforms!
じゃあ メイド服そろえないとだ！
M-Maid?
メ… メイド？
Since all the girls'll be wearing them!
女子全員で着るんだもんね
All the girls?!
女子全員？　ということは 私も…
Does that include... me?
おえ～ 無理　戦力外すぎる
N-No way!
Too far outside my skill set!
Grave Cafe
This way to the afterlife
Maybe if it was a grave cafe...
冥途喫茶なら貢献できそうだけど…
A-Afterlife for two...
Souvenirs from the grave available...
あの世へ２名ご案内
冥途の土産も販売中で～す
って 危ない危ない
また意識が飛ぶところだった
Crud, that was close.
I almost spaced out again.
And if anyone wants to perform on the
second day of the culture festival,
それと 文化祭２日目に行われる
体育館ステージでの
出し物の件ですが
あっ
• Theater Play
• Whack-A-Mole
• Yoyo
• Stamp Rally
• Photo Booth
• Hot Dogs
• Maid/Butler Cafe
• Haunted House
• Candy Shop
make sure you put one of these forms in
the box in front of the student council room.
やりたい人は
生徒会室前のボックスに
この用紙を入れてください
Perform on-stage as a band...
は～い
個人の出し物…
バンド 中学では
結局 １回もできなかったな
I never got to do it in middle school.
But I daydreamed about it a thousand times,
so same thing, right?
まあ でも…
妄想では1000回以上したし いいか
You feelin' the hype, arena?
盛り上がってるかい？　アリーナ
Besides, I play in real venues now!
それに今
ライブハウスでライブしてるし
My band's not for fun and games!
私はバンドを遊びで
やってるんじゃない 本気で…
It's serious business!
If someone from our class played,
they'd be the coolest person ever!
クラスの誰かがライブとかしたら
私 ほれちゃうかも
Totally!
だね～
えっ？
うわあ～っ！
How'd I end up at the student council room?!
なんで 私 生徒会室の前に？
何？　この紙
What's this piece of paper?
Stage Performance Application
Please Circle Desired Day
10/1  •  10/2
Band Performance
Kessoku Band
Hitori Gotoh
A band performance application...
“バンド出演希望 結束バンド”…
Kessoku Band...
って 誰？　こんなの書いたの！
Who wrote all this?!
What? Hitori Gotoh wrote it?!
えっ 後藤ひとりが？
I'm a professional guitarist now!
私は硬派な
ギタリストなんだ！
文化祭で ちやほやされたい
なんて煩悩は消せ！
Begone, lust for culture festival attention!
バンド活動に集中しろ！
Focus on your band's career!
Good... the lust is fading.
ほら 煩悩が薄れ… て…
What was that?
なんの音？
わっ！
Teacher! Someone's collapsed out here!
先生 誰か倒れてるんですけど！
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#10 After Dark
（イヤホンから漏れる
結束バンドの曲）
An unfamiliar ceiling.
知らない天井だ…
Hey, you're awake?
あっ 目 覚めた？
How are you feeling?
どう？　具合は
I'm f-fine.
あっ 全然 大丈夫です
後藤さん倒れたって聞いて
心配しちゃった
I heard you collapsed, so I got worried.
S-Sorry.
す… すみません
あっ
What's the matter?
どうかした？
いっ いえ…
N-Nothing...
ど… どうしよう
Wh-What do I do?
喜多さんに言ったら
絶対 参加しようって盛り上がって
If I tell Kita-san, she'll get
all excited, eyes sparkling,
目 キラキラさせて
話を進めてしまう！
and insist that we do it!
I m-must avoid that!
そ… それは避けたい！
Th-Thank you for coming.
あっ ありがとうございます
わ… 私 もう少し寝てから
バイト行きますので
I-I'll head to work after a little more rest.
ご… ご心配なく
D-Don't worry about me.
But won't you be lonely?
でも １人だと心細いんじゃ…
I'll b-b-be fine!
だっ だだだ… 大丈夫です！
た… 確か 喜多さん
今日は お友達と用事が
Y-You've got plans with friends today, right?
そうだけど
あれならキャンセルを…
Sure, but I can cancel them!
I'll b-b-be fine!
だだだ… 大丈夫です！
You're sure?
そう？　じゃあ 無理しないでね
Well, just take it easy, okay?
フウ～
I'd really like to perform,
本当は出たいけど
まだライブも ろくにしてないし
勇気が…
but I've barely done a real concert,
so it's still really scary.
Although...
でも 考えたら
Now that I think about it,
all the performers in a high school
culture festival are amateurs.
高校の文化祭に出るのって
全員 素人だよね？
I wonder what the vibe is like...
どんな雰囲気なんだろう
Y'all
(Hipster Kid)
What's up, y'all?
お前ら～！
うわっ！
Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement  Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement  Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement  Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement
F
e
l
t
h
盛り上がってるか～？
イエ～イ！
Ready to feel the hype?!
e
H
y
p
e
Yeah!
今日は お前らと
とびっきりの思い出 作ってくんで
We're
We're gonna make one hell of a memory today!
gonna make
O
n
e
h
l
o
f
a memory
today!
Join me on this journey!
よろしくな～！
J
o
i
n
me!!
Nope. I'm so worn out,
I can't even watch the concert.
無理…
心が削られて
ライブシーンまで行けない
But a loner-type shining at the
culture festival is a classic trope!
いや でも
ネクラが文化祭で活躍するって
王道展開だし 私にもいける？
So maybe I can do it too?!
お次は結束バンドのライブです
Next up, Kessoku Band performs!
On drums, Nijika Ijichi
from Shimo-Kitazawa High!
ドラムは下北沢高校の
伊地知虹夏ちゃん
Wah!  Squee!  So pretty!  So cute!  Look at me!  Waaah!  Wahhh!
Hi there!
ど～も～！
And Ryo Yamada, from the same!
同じく
ベース 山田リョウさん
Mini-bow.
ペコリ
And on lead guitar, from Class 2... Um...
そして
リードギターの２組の…
えっと… あっ 後藤さん
Oh, Gotoh-san!
あっ えっ…
And on guitar and vocals, from Class 5,
our school star, Kita-chan!
そして ギターボーカルは５組の…
So cute!  Eee!  Squee!  Waaaaah!  Eee!  Eeee! Waaah!
いや 我が校の星
喜多ちゃんだ～！
It's Kita-chan!
ありがと～！　フフッ
We love you!
Thanks, guys!
Kita-chan!                    Kita-chan!
The fervor gap is too intense!
露骨な温度差！
Yeah. Not happening.
うん 無理だ
I gotta know my place.
私には私に ふさわしい場所が
あるってことで
ん？
Good morning, Manager.
あっ 店長さん おはようございます
えっ 仕事してよ
Uh, could you do some work?
If you're already on the fence,
I think you should do it.
迷ってるくらいなら
出たほうがいいと思うけどね
一生に一度の青春の舞台だし
These high school years will
be gone before you know it.
Yeah, maybe...
ですかね？
まっ 私は
高校 ろくに行ってないから
Not that I'd know, since I
barely cared about high school.
適当に言ってるけどね
I dropped out!
私は高校中退で～す
I asked the wrong people.
I could never drag myself
out of bed in the morning!
朝起きれなくて
相談相手 間違えた…
Huh?
あれ？
Bocchi-chan's talking to Sis?
お姉ちゃんと ぼっちちゃんが
話してる～ 珍しい
That never happens.
She's waffling about her culture festival.
文化祭のことを憂いているんです
Culture festival?
文化祭？
She's trying to figure out if
Kessoku Band should perform there.
結束バンドで文化祭ステージ
出るか迷ってんだってさ
あっ え…
文化祭のステージ？
Performing at a culture festival?
いいじゃん 出ようよ！
Sounds awesome! Let's do it!
Um... But...
いや でも…
フフッ
ライブハウスとは違う良さがあるよ
It's fun in a different way
from performing at a club.
Y-You've done it before, Nijika-chan?
に… 虹夏ちゃん
出たことあるんですか？
Yeah, in middle school.
うん 中学んときね
Same.
私もある
マイナーな曲 弾いて
会場 お通夜にしてやった
I played obscure songs and totally
bombed with the audience!
Why do you sound proud of that?
なんで 誇らしげ？
SMUGFACE
I've never played with Ryo
at a culture festival, though,
あたしも
リョウとは出たことないし
文化祭ライブ やりたいな～
so I'd love to play at this one!
えっ そうなんですか？
Really?
Well, we only recently formed Kessoku Band.
結束バンド組んだの最近だし
私もオリジナル曲
ここ以外でやりたい
I'd like to play my original songs
somewhere other than here, too.
Plus, it's a great chance
to advertise ourselves!
こういうバンドがあるって
知ってもらう いい機会だよ
But...
でも 高校の文化祭って
Don't you get expelled for playing
Disciplinary Notice
Class 1-2
Hitori Gotoh
Reason for Reprimand
For singing a song with extremely depressing lyrics
at a culture festival intended to hype people up,
the aforementioned is officially expelled
under article 50 of the school code.
青春ロックで盛り上げないと
退学なんじゃ…
something other than seishun rock
at a high school culture festival?
Of course not!
そんな校則はないでしょ！
I get why Bocchi's scared, though.
とはいえ
ぼっちの迷う気持ちも分かる
えっ？
下手したら… というか
There's a chance—a likelihood, rather—that
you'll be playing in front of a large crowd.
絶対 ここより多い人数の前で
演奏するわけだし
So you don't have to rush to a decision.
だから そんなに
焦って決めることでもないよ
Ryo-san...
リョウさん
正直 お通夜状態だったライブ
To be honest, I still have nightmares
about that concert I bombed.
たまに夢に見る
So you were just acting strong earlier?
強がりだったのかよ
Either way, just make sure
you don't have any regrets, Bocchi-chan.
まあ ともかく
ぼっちちゃんの悔いが
残んないのが一番だからさ
Wise words.
それは言えてますね
G-Got it.
わ… 分かりました
ちょっと考えてみます
I'll think it over.
うんうん
Right, right!
Nijika-chan wants to play
at the culture festival too.
文化祭ライブ
虹夏ちゃんも
やりたいって言ってた
I bet it'd feel pretty darn good...
絶対 気分いいんだろうな～
うん 私…
I...
I just can't do it!
やっぱりダメだ～！
I'm sorry, everyone.
みんな すみません
I thought I could do it
yesterday, but I can't.
昨日は いけそうな気がしてたけど
無理です
B-But Nijika-chan told me to make
sure I don't have any regrets,
で… でも 虹夏ちゃんも
私が悔いないほうに
って言ってくれたし
and if I blow it, I don't think I could
make it through the rest of high school...
大失敗したら 高校生活
耐えられる気がしないし
I'm already nervous
about playing in a club.
ライブハウスでの演奏も
緊張してガチガチなのに
文化祭ステージなんて…
The thought of being
on stage at a festival...
Yeah, just not happening.
うん やっぱり無理
Skyrocketing to fame!
Let's look into the members of Kessoku Band!
The unexpected past of super-popular guitarist
Hitori Gotoh, whose cool personality, skillful playing,
and raw lyrics have captured the hearts of fans!
Hitori Gotoh
Q. Did you know your high school classmate
Hitori Gotoh has become a famous guitarist?
Hitori Gotoh had become a famous guitarist?
Did you know your high school classmate
Wow, Gotoh-san was in a band back then?
えっ まさか
あの後藤さんがバンドしてたなんて
サイン もらっとけばよかった～
I should've gotten her autograph!
I'll just follow that model instead!
目指すのは こっちの路線でいこう
I like it.
悪くない　うん
Now that I've got a plan in mind,
I don't feel so bad about it.
目指す道が はっきりして
悩みも解消された
Good work, me!
よかった
Gotoh-san!
後藤さ～ん！
ん？
Morning!
おはよう！
お… おはようございます
G-Good morning...
How are you feeling?
体調は どう？
I got worried and stopped
by the nurse's office again yesterday,
昨日 気になって保健室に戻ったら
もう後藤さん いなくて
but you were already gone.
R-Really? I'm sorry...
えっ ああ そうだったんですか
ごめんなさい
Oh, and I turned it in.
あっ あと 出しておいたからね
えっ？
文化祭の個人ステージ！
For the culture festival performance!
We'll be on stage as Kessoku Band!
結束バンドで出場するのよね？
へ？
I just can't wait!
もう すっごく楽しみ！
The application must've fallen
in the trash can by mistake.
保健室のゴミ箱に
間違って入っちゃってたの
What a close call, right?
危なかったね
あああ…
Let's put on the best
culture festival concert ever!
文化祭ライブ 頑張りましょうね！
ああ… あああ～
So that's why she's been like that.
それで ずっと こんな感じなんだ
I was so sure she wanted to do it.
てっきり 出たいものだとばかり…
She seemed very excited yesterday.
Wh-What do I do?
I am a criminal.
ど… どうしよう
Right?
They're going to label me a murderer!
このままじゃ 私 人殺しだ
It's not too late to back out, is it?
今からでも 参加
取りやめればいいじゃん
They said you can't take it back
once you've applied...
一旦出したら 取り消せない
と言われてしまって
But I'll talk to them tomorrow.
でも 明日 話してみます
やほ～！
Hey-ho! Free booze, please!
タダ酒 飲ませて～
飲ませるか　消えろ
Hell no. Piss off.
Aw, c'mon!
ちょっと～
君のお姉ちゃん
ツン 激しすぎな～い？
Tell yer sister to be nicer!
You like havin' me around, right, li'l sis?
妹ちゃんは
私がいると楽しいよね？
帰ってください
そろそろ お店始まるので
Kindly depart. We're about
to open for business.
You've got a death glare
on par with Senpai's lately.
先輩に負けず劣らずの
目をするようになったね
Bocchi-chan!
ぼっちちゃ～ん
どした？　なんか心配事？
What's with her? Somethin' on her mind?
I volunteered us for the culture
festival against her will.
文化祭のステージに
私が勝手に申し込んでしまって
What? You gonna play there?
えっ 何？　ライブするってこと？
I c-can't do it.
む… 無理です 私には
Th-There'd be so many more
people than I'm used to,
いっ いつものハコより
多い人の前で
a-and I'm s-scared of performing in
front of people who know me at s-school.
し… しかも 学校での私を
知ってる人の前でライブするのが
こ… 怖くて
Bocchi-chan.
ぼっちちゃん
これ あげる
For you!
えっ？
この前のお返しに
Payin' you back for before.
今日 私のバンド ライブすんの
My band's playin' a gig tonight!
Wanna come see?
よかったら 見に来なよ
C-Can I?
い… いいんですか？
もちろん
'Course you can!
Same goes for all y'all.
はい 君たちもどうぞ
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
Let me pay you.
あっ じゃあ お金
Yes, for the tickets.
ですよね チケット代を
Aw, don't go there. It's a gift!
いいよ～ あげる あげる
But...
いや でも…
無理しないでください
Please, let us pay!
H-Hang on, do you think
I'm some kind of broke rocker
えっ 君ら 私のこと
女子高生から金巻き上げる
貧乏バンドマンだとか思ってんの？
who's gotta hustle money from teenage girls?
You mean you're not?
えっ 違うんですか？
Damn it! Senpai, one bottle of shochu!
クソ～！　先輩 焼酎 ボトルで！
Like hell, dumbass.
やるか　バカ
Anyhoo, it's fine!
とにかく 君たち安心しなさい
こう見えてもねえ
I might not look it, but our band's
pretty popular on the indies circuit!
私 インディーズでは
結構 人気バンドなんだよ
Right?
ねっ？
Yes, they have many hardcore fans.
はい コアなファン多めです
Which means we make our ticket quotas, easy!
ってことで
チケットノルマなんて余裕だし
物販でも稼いでるんだから
We even make money on merch!
Then why do you only drink the cheap stuff?
じゃあ なんで
いつも安酒ばっかり？
えっ…
And you use our shower, too.
それに シャワーも
うちで借りてくし
Pay rent.
家賃 払え
You never paid me back for your train fare.
この前の電車賃
返してもらってない
うっ！
Sounds like a hustle to me!
やっぱり 金
巻き上げてるじゃねえか！
あっ あ～ これには深い訳が…
Th-There's a reason for all this...
All my money goes to paying for the
equipment I break while playing drunk.
泥酔状態でライブするから
毎回 機材ぶっ壊して
全部 その弁償に消えてるの
So it's your own fault.
自業自得じゃねえか
ぼっちちゃん ほかに こいつから
返してもらってないお金ある？
Bocchi-chan, has she borrowed any more
money from you that she hasn't paid back?
N-No... she hasn't...
あっ いや
おねえさんからは もう…
うっ…
Garbage humans.
クズども
Apologize for your late repayment.
返すの遅くなって ごめんなさい
って言え
Sorry for our lateness!
遅くなって ごめんなさい
I-It's okay...
い… いえ
プハ～ッ　野口先生 南無…
Noguchi-sensei... farewell...
You really need to cut back.
っていうか 禁酒しろよ
You never used to drink before
you started playing concerts.
ライブ活動する前は
全然 飲んでなかったろ？
It can't be good for you.
体 壊すぞ
あ～ まあ そんなことは
どうでもいいじゃ～ん
C'mon, that's no biggie!
Now, let's all go to Shinjuku!
よし みんな 新宿にレッツゴー！
I can't hear you!
Do you think she can really play like that?
あんなふうになって
本当にライブできるんですかね？
You're supposed to say "go!"
ゴー！
Getting to see SICK HACK for free...
SICK HACKのライブ
タダで行ける 胸熱！
My soul is on fire!
SICK HACK? Is that the name
of Hiroi-san's band?
シク ハック…
それが廣井さんのバンド名ですか？
Yep!
I knew she was good
from our street concert...
そうだよ～
おねえさん…
路上ライブで
うまいことは知ってるけど
But I don't really know
what she sounds like.
どんな音楽してるか よく知らない
I'm kind of looking forward to this!
ライブ 楽しみかも
あ… 今日
ライブ すごく よかったです
I v-very much enjoyed the concert...
Thank you for having me...
ありがとうございました
We're not even at the venue yet!
まだ会場にすら着いてないでしょ！
Here's my home base, Shinjuku FOLT!
ここが
私のホーム 新宿FOLTで～す
C'mon in, y'all!
さあ 入って入って
The vibe is very different from Starry's...
STARRYとは
随分 雰囲気が違いますね
Hey, no worries. It's the same kind of place.
大丈夫 うちと変わらないよ
It is a little scary,
確かに ちょっと怖いけど
but I feel strangely confident.
意外と大丈夫かも
Clubs are the same wherever you—
ライブハウスは どこも一緒だ…
Th-Thank you for the wonderful concert!
す… すばらしいライブを
ありがとうございました
だから まだ始まってないって
Seriously, it hasn't started yet!
I w-was a fool to think
I'd grown as a person...
ちょ… ちょっとでも
成長したと思った私がバカでした
I'm sure they're nice people
if you talk to them!
Gin-chan! Mornin'!
銀ちゃ～ん おはよ～！
ああ？
Yeah?
I m-miss my sister!
お… お姉ちゃんに会いたい
It's gotten to Ijichi-senpai too!
ついに 伊地知先輩まで！
ん～？
This is the manager, Gin-chan!
この人 店長の銀ちゃんね
H-Hello!
あっ こんにちは
Oh, gosh, look at all the cute
little buddies you brought!
やっだ～ 随分かわいくて
ピチピチな お友達がいるのね
私 吉田銀次郎 37歳で～す
I'm Ginjiro Yoshida, 37 years old!
Punk rock's my genre of choice!
好きなジャンルは…
えっ？
パンクロックよ
見た目とのギャップに
頭 バグるよね？
The contrast between how he looks and talks
kinda shorts out your brain, right?
でも 安心して
But don't worry.
銀ちゃんは心が乙女な
ただのオッサンだから
Gin-chan's a nice old guy
with the heart of a pure maiden!
Hey, Hiroi.
おい 廣井
はい？
Yeah?
遅刻するなって
いつも言ってるよな？
For the millionth time, don't be late.
もうリハーサル
終わっちゃいましたよ！
Our rehearsal's already over!
Sorry!
ごめ～ん！
But it'll all work out, I bet!
Are these the members of Kessoku Band?
もしかして
結束バンドの人たちですか？
Y-Yes!
ああ はい
And you're...
えっと…
She's part of SICK HACK.
SICK HACKの人
I'm Shima, the drummer.
私 ドラムの志麻です よろしく
A pleasure.
It's such a pleasure to meet you!
あっ よろしくお願いします
最近 うちの廣井が
ご迷惑をおかけしているようで
I'm sure our Hiroi's caused
a lot of trouble for you.
If this will in any way make up for it...
Sh-She's so polite!
れ… 礼儀正しい
Oh, th-thank you!
Maybe the other band members balance her out?
メンバーで大体
キャラのバランス取れてるのかな？
I'm Eliza! I lived in England
until I was eighteen.
私 イライザ
18歳までイギリスにいました
今 日本３年目！　仲良くしてね
This is my third year in Japan.
Let's be friends!
日本に来てバンドするなんて
邦ロック 好きなんですか？
You came all the way to
Japan to be in a band?
Do you like J-Rock?
No. Actually, I came to Japan for Comiket!
ああ ノー
コミケ参加したくて 日本 来たの
I really wanna be in an anisong cover band!
本当は
アニソンコピーバンドしたいです
Eliza's always saying anisongs are
Japan's real bleeding-edge sound!
イライザは
アニソンこそが日本の最先端って…
The three of them are...
この３人って…
Balanced?
I bought this in Asakusa!
バランスいいの？
これ浅草で買ったの～
Nice one!
いいね～
やめなさい
Stop now.
お待たせしました
Here you are.
Thank you!
ありがとうございます
Look at all the people!
お客さん多いですね
There's at least two hundred here.
もう200人は いるね
I had no idea her band was this popular...
おねえさん
こんな人気バンドだったんだ
By the way, where's Ryo?
あれ？　そういえばリョウは？
She was with us just minutes ago...
さっきまで一緒にいたのに
Eh?
あれ？　あんな所に座ってる
She's sitting over there!
Sh-She's doing...
あっ あれは…
the club classic: the "I'm not like you
overexcited sheeple" customer!
ライブハウスに よくいる
“手前で盛り上がってるお前らとは
違うんだぜ”感を出す
通ぶりたい客
音を聴け 音を
Take in the sound. The sound!
リョウ先輩
Ryo-senpai.
What kind of band is SICK HACK, exactly?
SICK HACKって
どんなバンドなんですか？
They play psychedelic rock.
ジャンルはサイケデリック･ロック
A genre that spread in the 1960s as a musical
expression of drug-induced hallucinations
1960年代に流行したジャンルで
ドラッグによる幻覚を
音楽として体言化…
whose influence led to many progressive
rock bands getting their start...
I've never seen Senpai talk
so much about anything.
先輩って こんな
流暢に しゃべれたんですね！
は… 早く聴きたいですね
I c-can't wait to hear them.
Yeah!
うん！
I'm kinda interested in psychedelic rock!
サイケデリック･ロック
ちょっと気になります！
Really?
ホント？
I'll bring all my albums tomorrow.
じゃあ 明日
アルバム全部 持ってくる
It's best for a beginner
to start from the second.
初心者は２枚目から聴くのがベスト
Better watch what you say, Kita-chan.
喜多ちゃ～ん
気軽に そういうこと
言わないほうがいいよ～
That kind of line will get
you mobbed by fanatics.
めんどくさいオタクが
目 キタ～ン！　とさせちゃうから
うわあ！
きゃ～！
うお～っ 廣井～！
Up late doing spot-the-difference puzzles
♪ まちがい探しのよふかし
あらたのし
Oh, what fun
♪ まよいが…
A lost child beckons me to a land of dreams
Their band's amazing.
このバンド… すごい！
見失いそうになる変拍子を
完璧に たたくドラム
The drum's spot-on irregular time
signature that keeps you off-balance.
This-a-way, that-a-way
The emotional yet overwhelmingly
logical playing of the guitar...
感情的で
それでいてロジカルなギター
Which way is the way?
My life's run out of battery
And the bass forms a wall of sound
that supports it all.
そして 全てを支える
ベースの音の壁
But now it's time, let's party
But the most amazing thing of all...
I can't tell you how much
I admire your philanthropy
でも 何より すごいのは…
is her overwhelming charisma!
おねえさんの
圧倒的なカリスマ性！
All of you, all of you...
♪ ことです
For the time they're standing on stage,
Round and round and round, let's dance
ステージにいる間は
演者はヒーロー
performers are heroes!
Hot and sweaty and close, you swirl around me
A band really is
やっぱり バンドって
I've got toast spread thick with lies
the coolest thing ever!
最高に かっこいい！
Would you like to try?
♪ おひとついかが
There's only one ghost, and it's me
♪ わたしだけユーレイ
Bocchi-chan! How'd you like my show?
ぼっちちゃん
私のライブ どうだった？
あっ え… よかったです
I-It was great.
ん…
That was so good!
すごくよかったです！
Hey, what's got you so down?
ねえ～ なんか元気なくない？
Thanks!
ライブ ホントは よくなかった？
We stunk the place up after all?
N-Not at all.
いっ いや… 本当に最高でした
You really were incredible.
But I... er...
でも あっ あの…
ん？
You were really shining up there.
おねえさん
すごくキラキラしていて
I don't think I could... ever...
私なんか とても…
Lemme fill you in here.
私って 実はさ 高校まで
Up to high school, I was the gloomy misfit
sittin' in a corner of the classroom.
教室の隅で じっとしている
ネクラちゃんだったんだよ
えっ？
Could ya tell?
あっ やっぱ分かる？
I guess it's true what they say:
gloomy people attract.
陰キャ同士は引かれ合うって
ホントなんだな～
But sometimes I'd imagine what
my future was gonna look like,
でも あるとき
自分の将来 想像したら
普通の人生すぎて つまんね～
って絶望しちゃって
and I'd think, "C'mon, that's lame!"
あ…
真逆の生き方してやろう
って思ってロック始めたの
I started playing rock
to make my life's course do a 180.
At first, I was scared stiff of buying a bass
at the music shop or going into a club.
楽器屋でベース買うのも
ライブハウス行くのも
最初 めっちゃ怖かったし
酒 飲み始めたのも
The whole reason I started drinking was
to chill myself out before our first concert.
初ライブの緊張を
ごまかすためだしね
Everyone's scared when they
do something for the first time.
始めて何かするってのは
誰だって怖いよ
But you played just fine,
both on the street and at Starry!
でも ぼっちちゃんは
路上でも スターリーでも
ライブできたじゃん
And you didn't even need alcohol to do it!
しかも 酒に頼らず
You mean...
おねえさん…
Have a little faith in yourself!
自分に もっと自信持って
And if that's not enough,
have a drink to take the edge off!
無理なら酒でドーピングもあり！
あっ いや 未成年なので
I-I'm really too young.
But I'd like you to come to our
culture festival performance.
でも 文化祭ライブ
よかったら来てください
あっ
アハッ
ヘヘッ
Yeah, that's the way!
イエ～イ その意気だ～！
I'm adding 100,000 to your tab
for wall repairs.
壁の修繕費 プラス10万
加算しといたからね
Th-That one's partly Bocchi-chan's fault!
ぼ… ぼっちちゃんとの
連帯責任で～
えっ！
Okay!
よ～し！
ライブ見て
Now that the concert's got us all hyped up,
テンション上がったし
文化祭のセトリ 決めちゃおう！
let's plot our culture festival setlist!
Kita-chan said each band
gets fifteen minutes.
喜多ちゃんによると
ひとバンド持ち時間は15分
だから 大体３曲くらいかな？
So that's about three songs, right?
H-Hey...
あの リ… リョウ先輩に
分けちゃダメなんですか？
C-Can't I let Ryo-senpai have some of mine?
No!
ダメ！
ぼっちちゃんに ずっと
お金返してなかったんだから
She needs to learn her lesson
for bumming off of Bocchi-chan for so long.
少しは痛い目 見るべき
郁代～
Ikuyo...
うっ！
喜多ちゃん ダメなバンドマンに
引っ掛からないで
Kita-chan! Don't fall for our
wicked bandmate's tricks!
The three Bs to avoid in a boyfriend are
"bassist, bassist, and bassist," after all!
“彼氏にしちゃダメな３Ｂ”の
Ｂって
ベーシスト ベーシスト ベーシスト
のことだから
I'll never borrow money from anyone again.
もう 絶対 人にお金借りません
Then I gift you this.
じゃあ これだけあげる
うああ～
ええっ
You're kind, Nijika. I love you.
虹夏 優しい　好き
The legit gratitude is tugging
on my heartstrings, darn it!
ちょっと ガチで感謝されると
胸が痛むじゃん
もう～ たくさん食え！
Just help yourself already!
セトリなら決めてある
えっ？
I already know our setlist.
文化祭 出るかもって言われてから
ずっと考えてた
I've been thinking it over since
the culture festival came up.
おっ いいね
Nice!
We'll put a Bocchi guitar solo
in the second one.
２曲目には
ぼっちのギターソロ入れる
えっ？
ぼっちの見せ場
郁代とぼっち ２人の文化祭でしょ
To make sure you shine.
It's your and Ikuyo's
culture festival, remember?
あっ…
あっ でも
文化祭で全曲オリジナルって
But isn't going all-original in the
culture festival a bit aggressive?
ちょっと攻め過ぎな気も？
いいじゃん
攻めの姿勢でいこうよ！
So what? Let's be aggressive!
And if we bomb, there's four of us.
スベっても４人いるし
痛みは四等分
We can split the shame four ways.
えっ！
Ryo, are you trying to push
your trauma on the rest of us?
リョウ みんなに同じ
トラウマ植え付けようとしてない？
Guitar solo...
ギターソロ…
あ…
ん？　き… 喜多さん？
K-Kita-san?
ご… 後藤さん！
G-Gotoh-san...
あ…
I...
私 後藤さんが
文化祭ステージの申込用紙
I knew you'd thrown out the
culture festival application!
捨てたって分かってたの！
でも わざと出したの
But I submitted it anyway.
ウソついて 本当に ごめんなさい！
I'm so, so sorry that I lied!
Th-Thank you for doing it.
あっ ありがとうございます
あ…
I w-was pretty freaked out at first,
あっ 最初は
どうしようって思ってたんですけど
but now I'm kind of looking forward to it.
今は ちょっと楽しみっていうか…
Th-That wouldn't have happened
if you hadn't turned in the application.
そ… それも 喜多さんが
用紙を出してくれたからで
So I'm really grateful.
だから 感謝してます
Thank you.
ありがとう
あ…
後藤さん 私
もっともっと練習 頑張るから
Gotoh-san, I'm going to work
even harder at practice than ever!
だから 文化祭ライブ
絶対 成功させましょうね！
So let's make our culture
festival concert a success!
O-Okay.
あ… はい
The truth is, I really wanted Gotoh-san
to perform at the culture festival.
私ね
どうしても 後藤さんに
文化祭ライブ 出てほしかったんだ
Because Gotoh-san is...
だって 後藤さんは…
Ryo-senpai!
リョウ先輩 バイトのあと
Would you be willing to coach me
on guitar after work?
私のギター練習
見てもらえませんか？
Isn't Bocchi coaching you?
ぼっちに見てもらってるじゃん
Gotoh-san has her own practice to focus on.
後藤さんも自分の練習あるし
I want to practice and get better too!
もっと練習して
変わりたいんです 私も
You heard her.
だってさ
つきあってあげたら？
Humor her, okay?
My lessons don't come cheap.
レッスン料 高いよ
はい！
Okay!
How come Bocchi-chan's not with you today?
そういえば 今日
ぼっちちゃん 一緒じゃないの？
Well... she's got make-up lessons...
はい… 後藤さん 補習で…
ああ…
えええ～っ！
31st Annual Shuka Festival
Bocchi-chan's missing?!
ぼっちちゃんが消えた？
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
Hey, why doesn't it stop?
The rhythm that I can't stop
keeps reverberating through my body
The melody playing in my earphones
is the only thing that lets me be who I am
The sky is tinged in red
But what color is my soul?
Tell me
where should I go?
I've always been searching
for something precious (hey!)
If everything's going to be lost some day
let's engrave it as deep as we can (now!)
My most pathetic nights
and cackling laughter
And days when I couldn't say
more than "You know..."
(I'm alive now, yeah Springtime of life)
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
#11 Duodecimal Sunset
見てください
Watch it.